https://www.recltd.co.uk/privacy-notice/

Cookie and Data Protection Policy - Resource and Environmental Consultants Limited (REC Ltd)
Contact
call:
0845 676 9303
email: info@recltd.co.uk
call:
Privacy Notice
For more information:
INTRODUCTION AND SCOPE
At RESOURCE AND ENVIRONMENTAL CONSULTANTS LTD., A CONCEPT LIFE SCIENCES COMPANY, (referred to in this Privacy Notice as “REC, “we” or “us”) we take your privacy seriously. We see it as our duty of care to keep personal data safe and to ensure that all personal data is used and stored in accordance with applicable data protection laws. Our culture of respect means we do not misuse personal data in our possession.
We appreciate the interest you have shown in us, our products and services by visiting us at recltd.co.uk (the “Website”) or by reading any of our online communications through channels such as our social media pages (collectively the “Online Channels”). This Privacy Notice explains what kind of personal data is collected and how it is used by REC when you interact with us, such as through visiting our Website, your use or purchase of our products or services, your contact with customer support, your subscription to our newsletters, your participation in our webinars or any other interaction with REC , including without limitation all online and offline collection of personal data, and your rights in respect of your personal data. This Privacy Notice does not apply to personal information for job candidates obtained through our Careers [https://www.recltd.co.uk/careers/], which is subject to the REC  Recruitment Privacy Notice (available: here).
This Privacy Notice may be changed over time and was last changed on 25/05/2018. The most up-to-date- Privacy Notice is published on our Website and we encourage you to periodically review the Website for any changes to this Privacy Notice.
2.  WHO WE ARE
RESOURCE AND ENVIRONMENTAL CONSULTANTS LTD., A CONCEPT LIFE SCIENCES COMPANY is a knowledge-based, science-led business providing a wide range of innovative and integrated solutions to clients in the pharmaceutical, biotechnology, food, environmental, agrochemical, petrochemical, chemical and consumer products sectors. We also work closely with academic groups.
Formed in 2014, our business has expanded through a mix of organic growth and targeted acquisition. Today, we are home to more than 700 employees, working from ten sites across the UK, sharing a common focus on problem solving, quality, collaboration, communication and flexibility.
By bringing together teams of highly trained scientists, excellent laboratory facilities and an in-depth understanding of our core markets, we have created a business that is greater than the sum of its parts.  This synergy means we have the in-house resources to offer a range of integrated services to our clients.
Our operations are structured around two divisions. Our Integrated Discovery and Development Services division supports discovery and development in the pharmaceutical, biotechnology, agrochemical, chemical and consumer industries.  Our Analytical Services division provides an extensive range of integrated services to clients in the life sciences, food, industrial and environmental sectors.
3.  WHO IS RESPONSIBLE FOR YOUR PERSONAL DATA?
REC, based at 1based at Osprey House, Broadway, Manchester, M50 2UE, is the controller for the processing of personal that falls within the scope of this Privacy Notice.
If you have any questions about this Privacy Notice, your use of the Website, our products, services, solutions, events or your dealings with us, in relation to our use of your personal data or your rights in relation to your personal data, you can contact us via email at GDPR-Enquiries@conceptlifesciences.com.
4.  FOR WHICH PURPOSES DO WE PROCESS YOUR PERSONAL DATA?
4.1  FOR ANSWERING YOUR QUESTIONS AND FOLLOWING UP ON YOUR REQUESTS
What does this purpose entail?
If you get in touch with us at [GDPR-Enquiries@conceptlifesciences.com or via the contact form] on our Website, we will respond to your enquiry using your personal data.
On what lawful basis do we process personal data?
We process your personal data on the basis of our legitimate interest in managing our relationship with existing and potential customers, suppliers, vendors and business partners.
Which personal data do we process for this purpose?
For this purpose, we process your name, contact details, your correspondence with REC and any other personal data necessary for answering your question.
4.2  FOR PROCESSING YOUR ORDER AND PAYMENTS AND FOR DELIVERING CUSTOMER SERVICE
What does this purpose entail?
We use your personal data to process and deliver your order, report on order status and to contact you about the transaction (for instance, where the transaction fails), as well as for providing customer services.
On what lawful basis do we process personal data?
We process your personal data on the basis that it is necessary for performing a contract between you and us. If you fail to provide the requested information, REC will be unable to process your order and/or provide customer services to you.
Which personal data do we process for this purpose?
For this purpose, we process your name and contact details, credit card and other payment information, your acceptance of our applicable terms and conditions and your correspondence with REC.
4.3  FOR THE DEVELOPMENT AND IMPROVEMENT OF PRODUCTS AND/OR SERVICES
What does this purpose entail?
We process your personal data in order to assess and improve our products and services. We convert your personal data into statistical or aggregated data to analyse customer behaviour and to adjust our customer offerings. We also, on an aggregate basis (i.e. in a way that does not personally identify you), perform market trend research through statistical analysis to evaluate and adapt our products and marketing to new developments.
For this purpose, we analyse how often you read the newsletters and visit our Website, which pages you click on and what goods you purchased through our Website. Based on this information, we may make adjustments to our offerings, our newsletters or the Website as well as adapt our promotions.
On what lawful basis do we process your personal data?
We process your personal data on the basis of our legitimate interest in developing and improving our offerings to our customers in view of customer needs and wider market trends and developments.
Which personal data do we process for this purpose?
For this purpose, we process your contact details, personal details (such as name and date of birth), payment information and transaction history, your demographic data (such as your country and preferred language), and your correspondence with us. We also process data generated from your usage of the Website such as IP address, webpages visited, your click-and-surf behaviour and the length of your session.
4.4  TO DELIVER YOU OUR WEBSITE’S FUNCTIONALITIES AND FOR ITS TECHNICAL AND FUNCTIONAL MANAGEMENT
What does this purpose entail?
We process your technical data to offer you our Website’s functionalities and to allow our Website administrators to manage and improve our Website’s performance. If you enter data in our Websites (such as product preference or your location) to receive relevant information or functionalities, REC processes this data to provide you with the requested information or functionalities.
On what lawful basis do we process your personal data?
We process your personal data on the basis of our legitimate interest in maintaining our Website’s functionality and being able to process payments via our Website.
Which personal data do we process for this purpose?
For this purpose, we process the personal data you have entered into our Website or that is generated from the functionalities you have used on the Website and the technical data from your device such as your IP address, the internet browser you use, pages visited on the Website, your click-and-surf behaviour and the length of your session.
4.5  WHERE APPLICABLE, TO OPEN AND ADMINISTER YOUR WEBSITE ACCOUNT AND TO MAINTAIN ITS CONFIDENTIALITY
What does this purpose entail?
You need to provide us with your personal data if you choose to register and open an account with us. Upon creating your account, we will send you your personal login information. We also use your personal data to administer and secure your account – for instance, we are able to change your password for you.
On what lawful basis do we process your personal data?
We process this on the basis of our legitimate interest in (i) managing our customer relationships through effective account management and (ii) protecting the confidentiality and integrity of our information networks, including the Website accounts.
Which personal data do we process for this purpose?
For this purpose, we process your name, email address, title, telephone number, gender and date of birth, address, any other information you have added to your account, your login data and credentials for security (such as your passwords, password hints and similar information) which enables us to authenticate you and provide you with access to your account.
4.6  FOR CUSTOMER RELATIONSHIP MANAGEMENT
What does this purpose entail?
REC will send communications to you for the purpose of performing relationship and account management as well as communicating recalls where necessary.
On what lawful basis do we process your personal data?
We process this on the basis of our legitimate interest in establishing and maintaining ongoing customer relationships.
Which personal data do we process for this purpose?
For this purpose, we process your name and contact details, personal details such as your name and date of birth, contact preferences, payment information and transaction data, whether or not you opt to receive our newsletter and your correspondence with us.
4.7  FOR DIRECT MARKETING PURPOSES
What does this purpose entail?
Our range of products, services and solutions is constantly evolving to match the increasingly sophisticated markets in which we operate. For this purpose, we may provide you with information about the same or similar products, services, solutions, promotions and offers, to those which you have received or about which you have enquired and which may be of interest to you.
We may also invite you to take part in market research or request feedback on our events, products, services and solutions.
On what lawful basis do we process your personal data?
We usually process your personal data on the basis of your consent, which you may withdraw by opting out of receiving marketing messages at any time and free of charge. We may, however, in limited cases, send you marketing messages without your consent being required. You will always have the option to opt out of receiving these communications by following the instructions included in each communication. Should you wish to opt out, we will no longer send you direct marketing.
Which personal data do we process for this purpose?
We process your name and contact details, your payment, order and transaction history, data generated from market surveys.
4.8  FOR ORGANISATIONAL ANALYSIS, MANAGEMENT REPORTING, ACQUISITION AND DIVESTITURES AND FOR THE EXECUTION OF BUSINESS PROCESSES AND INTERNAL MANAGEMENT
What does this purpose entail?
At REC, we process your personal data in the preparation and performance of management reporting and analysis using aggregated personal data. We also conduct customer, supplier and business partner surveys to learn more about your views and opinions as part of the reporting process. Additionally, your personal data may be processed in the context of mergers, acquisitions and divestitures, and in order to manage such transactions.
We process your personal data in the general performance and internal administration of our business, including in relation to asset and order management. Furthermore, your personal data may be used when we conduct audits and investigations to comply with applicable legal obligations and/or REC’s internal policies, implement business controls, and for managing our customer, supplier and business partner.
We also process your personal data for finance and accounting, archiving and insurance purposes, legal and business accounting and in the context of dispute resolution.
On what lawful basis do we process your personal data?
We process your personal data in order to satisfy our legitimate interest in operating the day-to-day business of REC and to develop and implement plans for strategic growth.
Which personal data do we process for this purpose?
For this purpose, we may process your contact details, personal details (such as your name and date of birth), payment and transaction data (including credit and payment information and order history), your response to our surveys, data stored on REC’s IT systems, data generated during the performance of your agreement with REC and your correspondence with REC.
4.9  TO COMPLY WITH THE LAW
What does this purpose entail?
REC processes your personal data to comply with laws and regulations (such as tax and business conduct-related and due diligence obligations including know your customer requirements) and this may involve disclosing your personal data to government or other supervisory authorities.
On what lawful basis do we process your personal data?
We process your personal data to comply with any legal or regulatory obligations to which we may be subject.
Which personal data do we process for this purpose?
For this purpose, we process your contact details, such as your address and email address, personal details, such as your name and date of birth, payment information, transaction history (including your order history), and your chamber of commerce and tax details, and any other information requested by the relevant government or supervisory authority.
4.10  TO PROTECT HEALTH, SAFETY, SECURITY AND TO ENSURE INTEGRITY
What does this purpose entail?
Where you are invited to REC’s premises, we process your personal data in order to safeguard our employees, customers, suppliers and business partners as well as their assets. As such, we authenticate your access rights to our premises and may screen your personal data against publicly available government and/or law enforcement agency sanctions lists.
On what lawful basis do we process your personal data?
We process your personal data in line with our legitimate interest in safeguarding the health and safety of others, as well as in authenticating third party status and access rights whilst on our premises.
Which personal data do we process for this purpose?
For this purpose, we process your name, date of birth, payment information and transaction history, and your visiting history to our premises.
5.  FOR HOW LONG DO WE RETAIN YOUR PERSONAL DATA?
We will retain your personal data for as long as necessary for the purposes set out above and as communicated to you at the time of collecting your personal data.
The criteria we use to determine data retention periods include the following:
Retention in case of queries: we may retain your personal data for a reasonable period after you have enquired about events, products, services or solutions, in cases of follow up queries from you.
Retention in accordance with legal and regulatory requirements: we will consider whether we need to retain your personal data after the period of retention in case of queries (above) due to legal or regulatory requirements which may be subject to. Some or all of these criteria may be relevant to retention of your personal data collected from you in connection with our events, products, services, solutions and/or your use of our Website.
Retention permitted under applicable law: we will continue to retain your personal data where necessary to provide our services to you and the retention of such personal data is necessary for pursuing our legitimate interests or where it is necessary for public interest purposes.
6.  COOKIES
We also collect information through the use of cookies. Cookies are small files of information which save and retrieve information about your visit to our Website – for instance, your internet service provider’s domain name, pages you accessed and when. We may process data we collect to give you a more seamless, consistent and personalised experience such as providing you with personalised recommendations based on your use of the Website.
Read more about how we use cookies and how you can disable them in our Cookie Notice, which can be found here.
7.  WHO HAS ACCESS TO YOUR PERSONAL DATA?
7.1  ACCESS TO YOUR PERSONAL DATA WITHIN REC AND SPECTRIS PLC (“SPECTRIS”)
Your personal data will be available within REC to only those who need access to the data and only to the extent necessary to meet the purposes specified in section 4 “For which purposes do we process your personal data?” (above). We will take appropriate measures to ensure that your personal data is appropriately safeguarded.
We may also share your personal data with our affiliates within the Spectris plc group of companies (of which REC is an operating company). We may exchange your data for administrative purposes and so that we can have a complete overview of your contacts and contracts with the Spectris group. This allows us to offer you a complete package of services and products. Where our affiliates send you information in relation to events, products, services or solutions that may be of interest to you, such disclosures will be pursuant to your consent (where required, in accordance with applicable laws).
In addition, as part of a Spectris group-wide data protection compliance programme, REC is party to the Spectris Binding Corporate Rules (the “BCR”), meaning that your personal data is treated with the same degree of care – regardless of where processing takes place – as long as your data is transferred within the Spectris group.
7.2  ACCESS TO YOUR PERSONAL DATA BY THIRD PARTIES
The following third parties have access to your personal data, where relevant:
Affiliates, distributors or agents, for instance, if we deem this necessary for offering you a complete solution for the business needs presented by you, or with our agents for servicing the products you purchased
Banks
Insurance companies
IT suppliers, including website administrators
Accountants and forensic specialists
Governmental and regulatory bodies and other third parties to whom we must disclose information under applicable law, such as to comply with a court order or a request from a regulator or similar legal process, or otherwise where necessary to comply with a legal obligation or for the administration of justice
Third parties concerned or their professional advisers, in the event of a merger, acquisition or any form of sale of some or all of our assets.
Where third parties are given access to your personal data, REC will take the required contractual, technical and organisational measures to ensure that your personal data are only processed to the extent that such processing is necessary. If your personal data is transferred to a recipient in a country that does not provide an adequate level of protection for personal data, REC will conclude agreements with the relevant third parties involved, limiting the purposes for which your personal data can be used and disclosed, and requiring your personal data to be appropriately safeguarded.
7.3   PERSONAL DATA OBTAINED FROM THIRD PARTIES
We work closely with third parties (including business partners, sub-contractors in technical, payment and delivery services, advertising networks, analytics and search information providers) and may receive personal data about you from them. Such data obtained from third parties will be kept in accordance with the same duty of care as described in this Privacy Notice, and with any additional restrictions imposed by the third party that shared your personal data.
8.  HOW IS YOUR PERSONAL DATA SECURED?
REC has taken adequate safeguards to ensure the confidentiality and security of your personal data. REC  has implemented appropriate technical, physical and organisational measures to protect personal data against accidental or unlawful destruction or accidental loss, damage, alteration, unauthorised disclosure or access as well as all other forms of unlawful processing (including, but not limited to, unnecessary collection) or further processing.
We use the industry-standard security protocol Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) to encode more sensitive information, such as credit card numbers for online purchase transactions via the Website. We employ the latest 128-bit encryption technology in all areas of the Website, which require you to provide personal or account information. This means that the credit card information you send is encrypted by your computer, and then decrypted again on our side, which limits the risk of others from accessing your private information when in transfer. You can verify this by looking for a closed lock icon at the bottom of your web browser or looking for “https” at the beginning of the address of the web page.
While we use encryption to protect credit card numbers and similar transaction information, please be aware that no method of transmission over the Internet is 100{e56040049d2bd1cefe8a397fbf7aeb0cd0861f8b0598f2148e35f875d415f790} secure. Although we take reasonable security measures to protect your personal data when we receive it, you also need to ensure you take appropriate steps to protect your personal data.
9.  LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES
Our Online Channels may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over the other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information that you provide while visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this Privacy Notice. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy notice applicable to the website in question.
10.  YOUR RIGHTS
You have a number of rights under applicable data protection law in respect of our processing of your personal data. These include:
the right to request access to your personal data;
the right to request rectification of any personal data that we hold;
subject to certain conditions:
the right to request erasure of your personal data;
the right to request restriction of processing of your personal data;
the right to have your personal data transferred to another controller;
where we rely on your consent for processing, the right to withdraw such consent; and
the right to lodge a complaint with a data protection authority (in the United Kingdom this is The Information Commissioner’s Office). A list of other authorities can be found here.
Further details on the scope of these rights can be found in the Concept Life Sciences Data Subject Request Form. Should you wish to exercise your rights, please complete the Request Form and send (including any supporting documents) to the Data Protection Manager: GDPR-Enquiries@conceptlifesciences.com. Note that, in order for us to respond to your request, we may require you to verify your identity.
Please be aware that some (or all) of these rights may not be available to you in your jurisdiction. Furthermore, we may reject requests that are unreasonably repetitive, require disproportionate technical effort (for example, developing a new system or fundamentally changing an existing practice), risk the privacy of others, or would be extremely impractical (for instance, requests concerning information residing on backup systems).
Data Protection Principles
Ensuring that we comply with the eight data protection principles, as listed below
Meeting our legal obligations as laid down by the Data Protection Act 1998
Ensuring that data is collected and used fairly and lawfully
Processing personal data only in order to meet our operational needs or fulfill legal requirements
Taking steps to ensure that personal data is up to date and accurate
Appropriate retention periods for personal data
Ensuring that data subjects’ rights can be appropriately exercised
Providing adequate security measures to protect personal data
Ensuring that a nominated officer is responsible for data protection compliance and provides a point of contact for all data protection issues
Ensuring all staff are made aware of good practice in data protection
Providing adequate training for all staff responsible for personal data
Ensuring that everyone handling personal data knows where to find further guidance
Ensuring that queries about data protection, internal and external to the organisation, are dealt with effectively and promptly
Regularly reviewing data protection procedures and guidelines within the organisation
Cookie Policy
What are cookies?
This website uses cookies to store information on your computer. Cookies are pieces of information that a website transfers to the cookie file on your computer’s hard disk. Cookies enable users to navigate around websites and (where appropriate) enable us to tailor the content to fit the needs of visitors who have accessed the Site and help us improve the user experience. We will not use cookies to collect information personally identifiable to you.
There are two types of cookie:
Session Cookies: These cookie files are erased when you close your browser. This cookie stores your browsing information and will be active until you leave a site and close your browser.
Persistent Cookies: These files stay in one of a browser’s subfolders until they are deleted manually or your browser deletes them based on the duration period contained within the persistent cookie’s file. You can set your browser to automatically remove these cookies when you log off.
For more information about cookies please visit https://www.allaboutcookies.org/ or follow these simple steps:
1. Click Tools & select Internet Options
2. Click the Privacy tab and select Advanced
3. Click Override automatic cookie handling
4. Specify how you wish to handle cookies from first-party Websites and third-party Websites
What Cookies are used?
Google Analytics – We like to anonymously keep track of user behaviours to help us keep our site content relevant and up to date. It is also useful to identify trends of how people navigate through our site.
If you don’t want Analytics cookies to be used when visiting our site, you can remove them by following this link: httpss://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout
@RECLtd
CONTACT US Osprey House
Pacific Quay, Broadway
Manchester, M50 2UE
0845 676 9303
Social Twitter
LinkedIn
Links Privacy Notice
© REC 2020. All world rights reserved.Delivered by Forest.
